Guide to the Lars Onsager Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lars Onsager papers
1926-1977
MS 794
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16
(16,000 frames)
The papers consist of correspondence, research materials for articles and lectures, teaching materials related to Yale University and the University of Miami, and citations for awards received by Lars Onsager, notably the Nobel Prize in 1968.
Onsager, Lars, 1903-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by Margarete Adleter Onsager, 1977 and 1979.
Scope and Contents
Lars Onsager was Yale University's first resident Nobel Laureate, receiving the prize in chemistry in 1968 for his discovery of the Onsager reciprocal relations in the thermodynamics of irreversible processes. His papers are almost entirely related to his professional career and contain research materials, descriptions of his scientific projects, writings and speeches. While the range of materials coincides almost exactly with his long tenure at Yale University, the bulk of the papers are concentrated in the 1960s and 1970s. The personal materials are confined to Series VII (BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL) which contains memoirs, interviews, photographs and family history. The papers are arranged in eight series.
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, contains only a small fraction of the letters that Onsager must have received and sent in his career. (Additional correspondence will be found in Series II-VI, filed topically as Onsager left it.) Most are from the mid-1960s or later. The incoming letters far outnumber the copies of the outgoing, and the latter are particularly concentrated in the last few years of Onsager's life. A few letters contain substantive scientific discussion, but most are routine.
Series II, RESEARCH MATERIAL, consists of scientific notes arranged by topic together with related manuscripts, correspondence and printed matter. Folders in this series are grouped in the following thirteen categories, each representing an area of Onsager's research:Dielectrics, Electrolytes, Ice, Irreversible Processes, Thermal Diffusion, Ising Model, Metals and Semiconductors, Liquid Helium, Hydrodynamics, Surface Tension, Origin of Life, Mathematics, and Unclassified. The contents of each folder remain exactly as Onsager left them; no reorganizing of the research material was done in any of the folders.
Series III, WRITINGS, consists of three sections:Publications, Pre-Publication Material and Lecture Series. The first two sections are keyed to the bibliography of Onsager's works published by the Royal Society in 1978. Also included in the papers are several titles not listed in the bibliography.Pre-Publication Material contains manuscripts and editorial matter preliminary to publication for about half of Onsager's publications, as well as several unpublished manuscripts.Lecture Series consists of edited transcripts of Onsager's classroom lectures at Yale University and the University of Miami. (Series II and IV also contain some texts of Onsager lectures.)
Series IV, CONFERENCES, contains correspondence, programs, abstracts, transcripts of papers and other documentation of scientific meetings. These papers are arranged in two sections:Onsager Text and No Onsager Text. In the first category the researcher will find either a text or abstract of a paper delivered by Onsager at the conference.
Series V, PROJECTS & INSTITUTIONS, consists of correspondence, financial records and memoranda of meetings connected with Onsager's activities as the principal investigator in numerous research projects. The sponsoring government agencies which awarded grants to Onsager include: the Air Force Office of Scientific Research, the Atomic Energy Commission, the National Institute of Health, the National Science Foundation and the Office of Naval Research. In addition to the records of his work at Yale University and the University of Miami, this series contains correspondence and other papers showing his participation in projects at other institutions: viz: the Neurosciences Research Program at MIT, as Fulbright Scholar at Cambridge University, Gauss Professor at the University of Göttingen and Lorentz Professor at the University of Leiden. His projects at Yale University are documented only from 1961.
Series VI, AWARDS & HONORS, consists of correspondence, programs, congratulatory letters and texts of presentations related to Onsager's receipt of the Nobel Prize and several other awards, as well as conferences arranged in his honor. Included here are also the texts of Onsager's lectures or remarks on these occasions.
Series VII, BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, consists of clippings, photographs, and biographical sketches.
Series VIII, WRITINGS OF OTHERS, contains preprints, reprints and other writings by scientists other than Lars Onsager. Some of the items carry a few words of greeting or dedication from the author. (Similar material is kept, as Onsager filed it, in Series I-II and IV-VI.)
The Lars Onsager Papers were deposited in the Yale University Library by his widow, Margarete Arledter Onsager in 1977 and 1979. Stefan Machlup of Case Western Reserve University and Philip A. Lyons, William W. Watson, Raymond M. Fuoss, Andrew Patterson, Jr. and Derek Leaist of Yale University kindly helped arrange the research material in Series II.
A tape recording of an interview with Onsager made after a Conference on the Theory of Irreversible Thermodynamics [1955?], made by Manuscripts and Archives from a copy in the possession of Stefan Machlup, has been transferred to Historical Sound Recordings.
The microfilm of the Lars Onsager Papers was produced by the Yale University Library Photographic Services Department during the summer of 1981 with funding provided by the Yale University Department of Chemistry. The film consists of material selected from the Lars Onsager Papers on deposit in Manuscripts and Archives and a few items loaned by the Kline Science Library. The papers were filmed in the order in which they are arranged as Manuscript Group Number 794. [1] A copy of the register, annotated with reel numbers, appears on the first reel of the film and serves as a guide to the film. [2]
In choosing material to be filmed the following criteria were used:
[1] Though all oversize material is stored in a folio at the end of the collection, on the film it appears in context with other related material
[2] After the filming a small amount of reprocessing took place; therefore a careful researcher may notice occasional discrepancies between the register and the film.
Biographical / Historical
Lars Onsager was a chemist and university professor. He taught at Johns Hopkins University in 1928; at Brown University, 1928-1933; and at Yale University, 1933-1972. Onsager was the winner of the Nobel Prize in chemistry in 1968. He was the recipient of numerous awards and honorary degrees, and the author of many articles.
Existence and Location of Originals
The originals are held by the family of Lars Onsager.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in eight series and includes restricted and oversize material: I. Correspondence, 1930-1976, n.d. II. Research Material, [pre-1930?]-1976. III. Writings, 1926-1977. IV. Conferences, 1935-1977. V. Projects & Institutions, 1946-1976. VI. Awards & Honors, 1952-1976. VII. Biographical Material, 1938, 1953-1978. VIII. Writings of Others, 1931-(1961-1976).
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Chemistry; Dielectrics; Electrolytes; Hydrodynamics; Ice; Irreversible processes; Ising model; Liquid helium; Mathematics; Nobel Prizes; Science; Semiconductors; Thermal diffusivity; Chemists; Educators; Abramson, Harold A. (Harold Alexander), 1899-1980; Coolidge, Albert Sprague, 1894-1977; Falkenhagen, Hans, 1895-; Onsager, Lars, 1903-1976; University of Miami; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Chemistry
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1930-1976, undated; Series I; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The arrangement is alphabetical by correspondent except that a few folders with topical headings are at the end of the series. Folders marked with an asterisk contain ten or more items from the denoted correspondent.
  - Abramson, Harold A.(*), 1930-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1)
  - Advances in Chemistry, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1)
  - Allen, George R., 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1)
  - Alpha Chi Sigma Fraternity, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1)
  - Altschuler, Aubrey P., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1)
  - American Academy of Achievement, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1949, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel 1)
  - American Journal of Physics, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5, Reel 1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6, Reel 1)
  - American Physical Society, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6, Reel 1)
  - American Scientist, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7, Reel 1)
  - Arledter, Hanns, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7, Reel 1)
  - Asakawa, Junko, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8, Reel 1)
  - Auslander, M. Arthur, 1970, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8, Reel 1)
  - Bauer, E., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9, Reel 1)
  - Baxter, Glen
    General note
    See: box 13, folder 181
  - Becker, R., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9, Reel 1)
  - Berman, Abraham S., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel 1)
  - Bernstein, Uri, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel 1)
  - Best, Charley, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel 1)
  - BioSystems (*), 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11, Reel 1)
  - Blanch, Gertrude, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12, Reel 1)
  - Blood, Frank A., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12, Reel 1)
  - Blüh, Otto, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13, Reel 1)
  - Blumenthal, Robert, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel 1)
  - Bose Institute, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel 1)
  - Braun, Charles L., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel 1)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15, Reel 1)
  - Brooks, Jack E.
    See: box 9, folder 96
  - Brun, Thorvald S., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15, Reel 1)
  - Bullemer, Bernhard, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16, Reel 1)
  - Burton, W.K., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16, Reel 1)
  - Careri, Giorgio, 1972, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17, Reel 1)
  - Carlin, Richard L., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17, Reel 1)
  - Chandrasekaran, T., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18, Reel 1)
  - Chen, Mou-Shan, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18, Reel 1)
  - Cole, Kenneth S., 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19, Reel 1)
    See: box 11, folder 144
  - Cole, Robert H., 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20, Reel 1)
  - Collective Phenomena, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21, Reel 1)
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21, Reel 1)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22, Reel 1)
  - Conceptual Physics, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22, Reel 1)
  - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 23, Reel 1)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23, Reel 1)
  - Coolidge, Albert Sprague, 1944-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 24, Reel 1)
  - Creekmore, Stephen, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25, Reel 1)
  - Czerlinski, George, 1969, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25, Reel 1)
  - Debye, Peter, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 25, Reel 1)
  - De Maeyer, L., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 26, Reel 1)
  - Deutsch, Daniel H., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26, Reel 1)
  - Devreese, J.T., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26, Reel 1)
  - Doering, W. von E., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 27, Reel 1)
  - Dole, Malcolm, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27, Reel 1)
  - Domb, C., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27, Reel 1)
  - Donnelly, Russell J., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28, Reel 1)
  - Dresden, Max, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28, Reel 1)
  - Drost-Hansen, Walter, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 29, Reel 1)
    See: box 8, folder 69
  - Drauglis, Edmund, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 30, Reel 1)
  - Ducker, W.L.
    See: box 9, folder 92
  - Dunker, A. Keith, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30, Reel 1)
  - Dunlop, Peter, post-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31, Reel 1)
  - Encyclopedia of Physics, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32, Reel 1)
  - Fajans, Kasimir, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32, Reel 1)
  - Falkenhagen, Hans(*), 1931-1933, 1947, 1954, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 33, Reel 1)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34, Reel 1)
  - Ferguson, Esmond S., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 34, Reel 1)
  - Fernandez-Moran, H., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 34, Reel 1)
  - Ferrer, Olga, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35, Reel 1)
  - Ferroelectrics, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 35, Reel 1)
  - Finkelstein, B.N., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 36, Reel 1)
  - Fisher, Frederick H., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37, Reel 1)
  - Fisher, Michael E., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37, Reel 1)
  - Flaig, Julian V., 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 38, Reel 1)
  - Flood, E. Alison, undated (Box 1, Folder 38, Reel 1)
  - Florida State University, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 38, Reel 1)
  - Foundations of Physics, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 39, Reel 1)
  - Fox, Sidney, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40, Reel 1)
  - Franklin Institute, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 41, Reel 1)
  - Frauenfelder, Hans, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41, Reel 1)
  - Free University of Berlin, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 42, Reel 1)
  - Friedman, Harold L., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43, Reel 1)
  - Friel, Edward, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 43, Reel 1)
  - Fuoss, Raymond M., 1934, 1937, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 43, Reel 1)
  - Furry, Wendell R.
    See: box 9, folder 78 See: box 9, folder 81
  - Gakken Co., Ltd., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44, Reel 1)
  - Garfield, Eugene, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44, Reel 1)
  - Gemant, Andrew, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 45, Reel 1)
  - General Electric Company, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 46, Reel 1)
  - Gibbs, J.H., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 46, Reel 1)
  - Glass, Leon, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 47, Reel 1)
  - Greathouse, Glenn A., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 47, Reel 1)
  - Gross, Eugene P., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 48, Reel 1)
  - Gunter, Roy C., Jr.
    See: box 6, folder 36
  - Gutmann, Felix, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 48, Reel 1)
  - Hartman, Hyman, [1976?] (Box 2, Folder 49, Reel 1)
  - Hassel, Odd, 1957, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 50, Reel 1)
  - [Haupen?], K., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 50, Reel 1)
  - Hedvall, J.A., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 51, Reel 1)
  - Hepp, Klaus, undated (Box 2, Folder 51, Reel 1)
  - Herzfeld, Karl F., 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 52, Reel 1)
  - Hill, Terrell, [1976?] (Box 2, Folder 52, Reel 1)
  - Hirschman, I.I., Jr.
    See: box 12, folder 161
  - Ho, Ren-jye, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 53, Reel 1)
  - Houston Memorial Lectureship Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 54, Reel 1)
  - Hubbard, Joseph, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 54, Reel 1)
  - Huberman, Bernardo A., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 54, Reel 1)
  - Hubmann, M., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 55, Reel 1)
  - Hückel, Erich, 1936, 1951-1952, 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 55, Reel 1)
  - Hui, Chui Shuen, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 56, Reel 1)
  - Hyman, Edward S., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 56, Reel 1)
  - Institute for Fundamental Studies Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 56, Reel 1)
  - Institute of History of Medicine & Medical Research, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 57, Reel 1)
  - Institute of Physics, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 57, Reel 1)
  - International Center for Theoretical and Solid State Physics, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 58, Reel 1)
  - International Society for the Study of the Origin of Life, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 59, Reel 1)
  - International Society of Quantum Biology, undated (Box 2, Folder 59, Reel 1)
  - International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 60, Reel 1)
  - Isihara, Akira, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 60, Reel 1)
    See: box 7, folder 53
  - Jebsen, Jens, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 61, Reel 1)
  - Jordan, Peter, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 61, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Applied Polymer Science, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 62, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Chemical Physics (*), 1936, 1959-1973 (Box 2, Folder 63, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Colloid Science, 1948-1972 (Box 2, Folder 64, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Mathematical Physics, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Membrane Biology (*), 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 65, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Physical Chemistry (*), 1935, 1949, 1955-1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 66, Reel 1)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1942, 1949, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 67, Reel 1)
  - Journal of the Electrochemical Society, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 68, Reel 1)
  - Journal of Theoretical Biology, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 68, Reel 1)
  - Kakiuchi, Yoshinobu, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 69, Reel 1)
  - Kallenbach, Neville, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 69, Reel 1)
  - Mascarenhas, Sérgio, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 70, Reel 1)
  - Kegeles, Gerson, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 70, Reel 1)
  - Kerker, Milton, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 70, Reel 1)
  - Kirkwood, James G., 1937-1959 (Box 2, Folder 71, Reel 1)
  - Knopf, Adolph
    See: box 13, folder 183
  - Kraemer, Elmer O., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 72, Reel 1)
  - Kramers, V.A., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 72, Reel 1)
  - Kratky, O., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 72, Reel 1)
  - Kraus, Charles A., 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 73, Reel 1)
  - Kron, Oskar, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 74, Reel 1)
  - Kursunoglu, Behram, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 74, Reel 1)
  - Lahoz, D.G., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 75, Reel 1)
  - La Mer, Victor K., 1932-1953 (Box 2, Folder 76, Reel 1)
  - Lamm, Ole, 1946-1956 (Box 2, Folder 76, Reel 1)
  - Landsberger Publishing Corporation, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 77, Reel 1)
  - Langmuir, [underline], 1938 (Box 2, Folder 77, Reel 1)
  - Lavenda, Bernhard, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 78, Reel 1)
  - Leibowitz, Leonard, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 79, Reel 2)
  - Lichtman, I.A., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 80, Reel 2)
  - Lieb, Elliott, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 81, Reel 2)
  - Lindemann, B., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 81, Reel 2)
  - Lipmann, Fritz, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 82, Reel 2)
  - Lobo e Silva, Roberto L., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 82, Reel 2)
  - Lorentzen, Hans Ludwig, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 83, Reel 2)
  - Lowe, I.J., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 84, Reel 2)
  - Lundgren, T.S., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 84, Reel 2)
  - McCauley, Joseph, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 85, Reel 2)
  - Machlup, Stefan, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 86, Reel 2)
  - McKeehan, Lewis, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 86, Reel 2)
  - MacRae, Duncan, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 87, Reel 2)
  - Malerba, Joseph F., 1973, undated (Box 3, Folder 87, Reel 2)
  - Mandel, M.(*), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 88, Reel 2)
    See: box 7, folder 51
  - Margenau, Henry, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 88, Reel 2)
    See: box 2, folder 51
  - Mark Twain Society, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 88, Reel 2)
  - Quatrième Conférence Internationale "de la Physique Théorique à la Biologie": transcript, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 89, Reel 2)
  - Mazo, R.M.
    See: box 10, folder 105
  - Mehl, Wolfgang, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 89, Reel 2)
  - Mehra, Jagdish, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 90, Reel 2)
  - Mehta, M.L., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 90, Reel 2)
  - Meijering, J.L., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 91, Reel 2)
  - Melehy, M.A., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 91, Reel 2)
  - Miller, Donald G., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 92, Reel 2)
  - Minagawa, Isao
    See: box 8, folder 70
  - Morowitz, Harold J., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 92, Reel 2)
  - Mott, N.F., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 93, Reel 2)
  - Murphy, Thomas J., 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 93, Reel 2)
  - Mysels, Karol J., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 93, Reel 2)
  - Nagle, John F., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 94, Reel 2)
  - National Academy of Sciences(*), 1947-1975 (Box 3, Folder 95, Reel 2)
  - National Defense Research Committee, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 96, Reel 2)
  - Nature, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 97, Reel 2)
  - Nederlands Tijdschrift voor Naturkunde, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 97, Reel 2)
  - Neuro Science, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 98, Reel 2)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1938, 1942, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 98, Reel 2)
  - Nishina Memorial Foundation, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 99, Reel 2)
  - Novak, I.J.
  - Odijk, T., undated (Box 3, Folder 100, Reel 2)
  - O'Reilly, Donald E., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 100, Reel 2)
  - Oster, Gerald
    See: box 5, folder 4
  - Parker, Peter, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 101, Reel 2)
  - Patterson, Andrew, Jr., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 101, Reel 2)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 102, Reel 2)
  - Pawlak, Zenon, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 102, Reel 2)
  - Physica, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 102, Reel 2)
  - Physical Review, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 103, Reel 2)
  - Physical Society of Japan, 1954-1955, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 103, Reel 2)
  - Pippard, A.B., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 104, Reel 2)
  - Polish Radio and Television, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 104, Reel 2)
  - Polytechnic Institute of New York, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 104, Reel 2)
  - Potts, R.B., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 105, Reel 2)
  - Price, Derek J. de Solla, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 105, Reel 2)
  - Price, P.J., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 106, Reel 2)
  - Prince, Jack, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 106, Reel 2)
  - Procter & Gamble Company, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 106, Reel 2)
  - Rasetti, Mario, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 107, Reel 2)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 108, Reel 2)
  - Research Corporation, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 108, Reel 2)
  - Reutter, F., 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 109, Reel 2)
  - Reviews of Modern Physics, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 110, Reel 2)
  - Robertson, Harry S., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 110, Reel 2)
  - Rockefeller Institute(*), 1930-1955 (Box 4, Folder 111, Reel 2)
  - Rockefeller University, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 111, Reel 2)
  - Rockstein, Morris, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 112, Reel 2)
  - Rothschild, K.J., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 112, Reel 2)
  - Roy, R.N., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 112, Reel 2)
  - Royal Society (London), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 113, Reel 2)
  - Royal Society of Sciences of Uppsala, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 113, Reel 2)
  - Saar, Robert, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 114, Reel 2)
  - Samaras, Nicholas T., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 114, Reel 2)
  - Scheider, Walter, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 114, Reel 2)
  - Scherrer, P., 1937, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 115, Reel 2)
  - Schindler, Dali, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 115, Reel 2)
  - Schmelzer, C. Christoph, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 116, Reel 2)
  - Schmitt, Francis, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 116, Reel 2)
  - Schnakenberg, Jurgen, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 116, Reel 2)
  - Schruben, Dale. L., undated (Box 4, Folder 117, Reel 2)
  - Science, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 117, Reel 2)
  - Selegny, Eric, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 118, Reel 2)
  - Senatra, Donatella, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 118, Reel 2)
  - Shamoo, Adil E., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 119, Reel 2)
  - Sherman, Seymour
  - Shin, Ernest, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 119, Reel 2)
  - Sigma Xi, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 120, Reel 2)
  - Siim, J. Chr., 1970, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 120, Reel 2)
  - Sion, Albert, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 121, Reel 2)
  - Society for Neuroscience, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 121, Reel 2)
  - Spicer, W.M., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 122, Reel 2)
  - Staebler, David L., 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 122, Reel 2)
  - Starzak, Michael E., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 123, Reel 2)
  - State University of New York at Albany, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 123, Reel 2)
  - Stewart, Andrew M., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 124, Reel 2)
  - Stey, G.C., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 125, Reel 2)
  - Stigter, D., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 126, Reel 2)
  - Stommed, H., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 126, Reel 2)
  - Suzuki, Masuo, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 127, Reel 2)
  - Sveriges Radio, undated (Box 4, Folder 127, Reel 2)
  - Syozi, I., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 127, Reel 2)
  - Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 128, Reel 2)
  - Temperley, H.N.V., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 128, Reel 2)
  - Texas Instruments Foundation, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 129, Reel 2)
  - Theodorsen, Theodore, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 129, Reel 2)
  - Thomas, Henry C., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 130, Reel 2)
  - Thomas, John M., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 130, Reel 2)
  - Thompson, James C., undated (Box 4, Folder 131, Reel 2)
  - Ting, Shin-Fan, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 132, Reel 2)
  - Tulinsky, Alexander, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 132, Reel 2)
  - United Nations University, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 133, Reel 2)
  - University of California, San Diego, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 133, Reel 2)